Graeme Thornber - Senior Web Engineer

Mobile: +6421 0292 4529

E-mail: thornberrypie@gmail.com **Website:** www.thornberrypie.com

Summary

Web Developer and Software Engineer with 16 solid years experience building and maintaining web applications in Auckland, Wellington, Germany and Whitianga.

I've worked with some of New Zealand's top digital and design agencies on many projects and campaigns for local and global clients. I'm full-stack but prefer building user interfaces over the devops side of things. My strongest skills involve communication, presentation, time management and complex problem solving.

I enjoy working with people as much as computers and have a genial, quirky sense of humour. My team wins the pub quiz most weeks and I regularly smash out a few tunes with my guitar at the local open mic night, as well as acting in the occasional theatre production..

Employment History

Senior Developer / Software Engineer

Tourwriter (2019-2023)

Over 4 years I worked with a local and virtual diverse Agile team to create version 2.0 of Tourwriter's core product: an online version of their legacy .NET offering.

Even though the business relies on international travel to exist, we managed to ride out the pandemic due to strong investment and a solid product still growing and loved by many tour operators all over the world.

I was instrumental in implementing many of the core features in a stack of React / Redux / Material-UI, created a Wordpress plugin for the product, then in 2022 completely overhauled the testing framework from Enzyme to React Testing Library.

Senior Full-Stack Developer

DNA Design (2017 - 2018)

Delivering solutions with a senior agile team and creating new features for some of New Zealand's largest public sector clients with Silverstripe CMS. I mainly worked remotely, in constant communication with the team on Slack, Jira and Skype as well as physically meeting regularly for project briefings, workshops and events like Codemania and Stripecon.

Lead Developer

Spitfire (2016)

Leading a small team of varying contract developers and designers I directed the development cycle of several projects from initial phases to completion, collaborating closely with clients as well as advising the management team on SEO, web standards and social media marketing.

Freelance Developer

Thornberrypie.com (2014 - 2015)

After living in Europe I spent some time as a contractor in Auckland gathering more varied skills and honing existing ones while assisting digital agencies to produce solid results in various campaigns and ventures.

Web Entwickler

Scopevisio (2011 - 2013)

I left for a second OE in 2011 and lived mostly In Bonn, Germany where I assisted a successful SaaS company with evolving the presence of their digital product. I converted their massive website from an old Java CMS to Drupal, as well as crafting HTML emails for Deutsche Telekom campaigns and working with the senior management team to construct a Cloud Services company website.

Lead Developer

+The Church+ (2010 - 2011)

Stepping in to relieve one of the founders and lead the direction of digital development, I collaborated closely with some amazing designers to produce outstanding websites and help sustain the reputation of +The Church+ which still remains today.

Front-End Developer

Solutionists (2008 - 2010)

Under the excellent mentoring of the company founders I fine-tuned the process of converting complex designs into dynamic websites, and over dozens of projects perfected the art of PSD to HTML while crafting CSS and jQuery for all browsers including IE6.

Freelancer

Thornberrypie.com (2007 - 2008)

After gaining a Web Development Diploma in 2006 and some valuable freelancing experience I quickly picked up the tricks of the trade and made the transition from my previous career in hospitality as a waiter, bartender and events coordinator.

Education

2005 – 2006 Natcoll (Auckland, New Zealand)

Diploma in Web Development

1998 - 1999 Auckland University

Psychology, Anthropology, Philosophy

1992 – 1996 Howick College (Auckland, New Zealand)

English, Computer Studies, Drama, Music, Japanese

Technical Skills

Expert:

- HTML5 with a focus on usability, SEO and accessibility best practices
- CSS3: SASS, LESS, Flexbox, CSS Grid, Pure.css, Bootstrap, Foundation
- Modern Javascript: ES6, React / Redux, Node, Typescript, Vue, Angular, ¡Query
- Testing tools: React Testing Library, Enzyme, Jest, ESLint, Prettier
- CMS: Wordpress, Silverstripe, Drupal, Joomla, Concrete5, Sulu, Bolt, Typo3
- HTML variants: JSX, Mustache, Handlebars, Underscore, Twig, Liquid
- HTML4 Email template creation, delivery with Campaign Monitor & MailChimp
- Git management and Agile team workflow: Jira, Slack, SCRUM, Kanban, Trello
- Communication: written & spoken, formal & creative, face-to-face & remote

Advanced:

- PHP, MVC frameworks Laravel, Symfony, Codelgniter, Zend, CakePHP
- Linux Server administration, Ubuntu, Nginx, Apache, MySQ (LAMP)
- MySQL, data management, NoSQL, MongoDB, Firebase, JSON, XML
- Design tools: Photoshop, Sketch, InVision, InDesign, Illustrator, Fireworks
- APIs & web services: REST, SOAP, Google Maps API, AWS, Rackspace
- CLI tools & compilers: Yarn, NPM, Webpack, Composer, Gulp, Grunt, Babel
- E-commerce: Shopify, Magento, OSCommerce, Zen Cart, DPS, Paypal

Intermediate:

- Mobile apps: React Native, Xcode, Swift, Java, Android Studio, Cordova
- Docker, PostgreSQL, pgAdmin, FeathersJS, Capistrano, Codeship, Beanstalk

Currently learning / very interested in:

- Flutter / Dart, React Native, Cross-platform development
- PostGIS and geospatial data mapping
- Game development with WebGL, Canvas, Phaser, Babylon.js

Other Skills & Hobbies

Music

I've been singing and playing guitar, piano etc for over 30 years. I played in a few bands over the years and continue to write songs, attend the local weekly open mic night and play the occasional solo gig.

Theatre

In high school I played Kenickie in Grease and took lead roles in other productions playing Hamlet amongst others. Since 2017 I've been involved in running a local improv group, attending drama workshops and acting in Whitianga's Offbeat Theatre productions.

Cooking

I learnt to cook by accident from working in fancy restaurants and memorizing menus. I'm constantly improvising in the kitchen and improving recipes, especially curries, gourmet salads and one of my specialties: Thai Pumpkin Seafood Chowder.

Communication

My strongest form of communication is through music but I also use telepathy and interpretive dance... and English when necessary. I'm fluent in German and have basic skills in many other languages such as Japanese, Portuguese and Italian.

Games

I have a passion (or rather obsession) for problem solving and am capable of intense focus and concentration. I love crosswords and word games, our team wins most weeks at the local pub guiz and I can probably beat you at Street Fighter 2.

Examples of my work can be found on my website at: www.thornberrypie.com